# **Louis Griffin**

louisgriffin12@gmail.com o linkedin.com/in/louisgrif

### **Snapshot**

Creative and quick-learning programmer with experience over a broad range of coding platforms and languages. Proven ability to adapt strategically to overcome the challenges of a given workplace and position, with a focus on well-structured development, and a passion for creating beautiful codebases that function efficiently. **Areas of experience include:** 

Javascript React Java

Figma UI/UX Algorithms

#### **Education**

**BS in Computer Science,** University of Wisconsin-Madison 2019 - May 2022

• Completed 15 courses in the major, graduating in 3 years. Courses Include:

Algorithms Compilers Databases

Computer Graphics Software Engineering User Experience

### **Work Experience**

#### Web Developer & Executive Board Member, JUST Journal Sept 2021 - Present

- Enhanced user interfaces allowing for a better flow of information and more enticing site
- Contributed heavily in executive board meetings, shaping the future of the organization by shifting the board's focus towards certain strategic goals and opportunities
- Recruited, interviewed, and identified successor candidate due to early graduation
- Wrote extensive documentation for use by the organization's future web developers
- Identified and fixed malicious files, successfully defending against a hack attempt

### Web Development Intern, MERGE Advertising Winter 2020, Summer 2021

- Worked closely with front-end dev team to rapidly gain fluency in javascript, react, and general web development despite no previous experience in the languages and/or field
- Created web-pages using a clean, component-focused style exactly to the specifications
- Assisted in designing user interfaces with a focus on storytelling, simplicity, and usability
- Participated in client meetings, strategizing after with the rest of the front-end dev team
- Focused on efficiency and effectiveness in order to make time for more responsibilities
- Ideated personal projects in order to learn intermediate styles and essential libraries including redux, firebase, material-ui, sass, storybook, jest and many others

## Leadership

#### Team Captain, Madison Esports Club

Jan 2021 - Present

- Built an amateur esports team from the ground up and handled all team responsibilities
- Oversaw all matches, practices, coaching, scrimmages, and post-game analysis
- Rallied team members, connecting them with suitable coaches and inspiring growth